Hasan Kataya

Software Developer - https://hkataya.github.io

Mouawad Street, Chiyah
Beirut, Lebanon
+96170046273
hasankataya10@gmail.com

Fast paced and a quick learner with a huge passion for software development. Aiming to leverage my proficiency in multiple programming languages, knowledge in various testing techniques and design principles, and experience with working in an agile way, to provide the best value for your company.

EXPERIENCE

LIBRO, Beirut — *Software Developer*

JUNE 2019 - OCTOBER 2019

- Designed and built the API backend (Node.js) for a platform that can easily be scaled.
- Used various testing strategies, integrated with a CI/CD pipeline, to assess performance and functionality.
- Worked in an agile way and used Scrum framework and Jira tool to collaborate on the project with the team.

FREELANCE, Beirut— Laravel Developer

DECEMBER 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020

- Built a web application to automate the 25/10 CrowdSourcing process.
- Developed using PHP/Laravel adhering to the MVC architecture.
- Incorporated a real-time layer using Pusher to add real-time data and functionality to the application.

PROJECTS

CourseShare —Cross Platform Desktop App

An offline-first, cross platform desktop application built using the latest web technologies (TypeScript, React, Redux), featuring a data sync strategy that allows users to share their data across multiple devices.

JBPM Process Workflow—Web App

A web application that allows users to create tasks and assign them to other users for approval, integrated with a business process management tool (JBPM).

SKILLS

Technologies & Tools:

JavaScript - TypeScript - Node.js React.js - Laravel - Java - JBPM Spring Boot - Linux Administration Databases (MongoDB, MySQL) Testing (Unit,Integration,E2E) CSS (Bootstrap, Materialize...)

Software Design & Architecture:

Model View Controller - Object Oriented Design - REST API Design Component Based Architecture SOLID design principles

Software Methodology & Tools:

SDLC - Agile - SCRUM - CI/CD Version Control - Jira

EDUCATION

Lebanese University
Computer Science Degree
OCTOBER 2017 - 2020

Beirut Modern School High School Degree JUNE 2017